# Rashmi AP

# Front End Web Developer, Bangalore









https://github/rashmiap



https://linkedin.com/in/rashmiap

## **Overview**

Experienced Front-end Developer with 3+ years of experience developing and managing web apps with a demonstrated history of working in the internet industry. Skilled in ReactJS, HTML and CSS. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's Degree focussed in Computer Science from B.M.S. College of Engineering.

# **Experience**

AmyGB.ai Nov 2018 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

Description: AmyGB Specializes in developing products in the area of Text & Vision with an aim to personalize offerings for enterprises, in a way that enhances their customer experience as well as engagement, while reducing the associated costs for an enterprise using machine learning including deep learning & advanced NLP to resolve high impact problems for an enterprise.

#### Contribution:

 Designed and implemented an Express/NodeJS microservice REST API for AmyGB sales website that handles creation, updates and retrieval of data on MongoDB. AWS SES was used to send transactional emails to requested end users.

## Roundglass ZoojooBE

Jan 2016 - Oct 2018

Software Engineer

Description: Zoojoobe is a game based social wellness platform that unites the workforce to form healthier habits. The psychology behind Zoojoobe is to enable peer-to-peer motivation allowing people to challenge, cheer and reward their colleagues and friends within their organisation.

#### Contribution:

- We are a small tight-knit team, so I got a chance to wear many hats, from requirement analysis to generating the build.
- Worked closely with Product Managers, UX Designers and Backend Engineers to develop pixel perfect User Interface.
- Worked on various features on the App like Social feed, Dare, Pregnancy module and Journey which were developed using ReactJS on the frontend stack.
- Developed and maintained the frontend of Zoojoobe sales website.

Caterpillar Inc. Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

Associate IT Analyst

Description: Being part of Caterpillar's Global Information Services(GIS) division, features required me to work across the mainframe stack with COBOL, the primary mainframe programming language which compiles to machine language, ISPF and JCL.

#### Contribution:

• Features required me to work across the mainframe stack with COBOL, the primary mainframe programming language which compiles to machine language, ISPF and JCL.

# **Projects**

## **ZoojooBe Social Stream**

Social stream is a feature that leverages on the social behaviour within the corporate allowing users to share media among the employees within a particular corporate. It allows user to post media, like, share, comment and subscribe to a particular post that keeps them motivated to do a particular task. Technology stack: ReactJS, Draft-is-plugins, DropzoneJS.

#### **ZoojooBe Dare Feature**

This feature which primarily focuses on the competitive behaviour lets users throw a fun challenge to their friends on the platform and earn points for each win. It allows user to pick or customise a dare and the reward. Meanwhile other users on the platform can motivate using the cheer functionality. Technology stack: ReactJS, Material-UI, AJAX.

### **Zoojoobe Journey Feature**

Journey feature on the Zoojoobe platform is a set of curated activities that are a set of micro-tasks that a user has to form to achieve a bigger goal like forming a complex habit. Journey feature has multiple levels which changes based on user activity. The whole task list is customised based on user activity. Technology stack: ReactJS, react-sound.

#### **Zoojoobe Pregnancy Feature**

This feature is an informative and reassuring guide to pregnancy. Full of the latest essential information, relaxing audio tracks and expert advice, it helps user to prepare for motherhood.

Technology stack: ReactJS, react-sound.

### **React Redux Movies and TV shows app**

This is a responsive movies and TV shows app built using ReactJS and utilizes Redux for state management. The Movie Database (TMDb) API is used to fetch data. You can navigate between the latest movies and the latest TV shows. Can view full details including cast members of each movie/TV show by clicking on 'See More' button. Can locally save and unsave any movie/TV show.

<u>Technology stack</u>: ReactJS, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Material-ui, TMDb api.

<u>Github link</u>: https://github.com/rashmiap/react-redux-TMDb-app

## **AudioDb Artist Search App**

This is a simple mobile responsive artist search app developed using AudioDB API built using ReactJS. User can also view all the albums of each user including track additional details.

<u>Technology stack</u>: ReactJS, Material-ui, AudioDB API.

<u>Github link</u>: https://github.com/rashmiap/audioDB-react-app

#### **Exercise Journal API**

A REST API that processes exercise activity which was part of the freecode curriculum. The frontend is built using HTML/CSS and is used to demo API functions. API is built using Node/Express and handles data creation, updates, and retrieval. Backend is a MongoDB document database that stores user and exercise data.

<u>Technology stack</u>: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose

<u>Github link</u>: https://exercise-rash-tracker.glitch.me

## **React MobX Movies app**

This is a responsive app that displays the latest upcoming movies. Developed using ReactJS and utilizes MobX for state management. The Movie Database (TMDb) API is used to fetch data. You can search for movie based on movie title. Can view full details including cast members of each movie clicking on 'See More' button. Can locally save and unsave any movie/TV show.

Technology stack: ReactJS, MobX, Material-ui, TMDb api.

Github link: http://mobx-tmdb-app.surge.sh/

# **Education**

B M S College of Engineering, Bangalore Computer Science and Engineering (CGPA: 9.12)

Treasurer, Fine Arts Club, 2014

2011-2015